SIDDHANT GUPTA

UX DESIGNER

Ever since I could first remember, I've been fascinated by how things work. While it took me some time to discover my passion for design, I haven't stopped pursuing it ever since. I am incredibly detail orientated and believe that small things can make the biggest impact.

After working in multiple companies, I've grown to be a **team-player** by being empathetic to others and being adaptive to my environment.

My experience derives from successfully delivering **dozens** of projects in different areas while still maintaining an agile approach. I like to learn & keep myself updated with skills, tools, trends and practices.

In near future, I see myself managing a design team aiming to elevate user experience across all mediums.

If I had to describe myself in one word, that'd be stalwart.

SKILLS

DESIGN

Sketch, InVision Studio, Figma, XD, Photoshop, InDesign

PROTOTYPING

InVision, MarvelApp, Framer, Proto.io, Origami, Webflow

UI DEVELOPMENT

Javascript, HTML, CSS, ReactJS, D3, Wordpress, Bootstrap

CORE DEVELOPMENT

Python, Django, C++, Clojure, ClojureScript, GIT

OTHER SKILLS

Machine Learning, Analytics, AutoCAD, CATIA, Final Cut Pro

SOFT SKILLS

Public Speaking, Presentation, Formal Writing, Leadership

LANGUAGES

English (native), Finnish (beginner), Hindi

EDUCATION

2017 - 2019

M.SC. HUMAN COMPUTER INTERACTION & DESIGN
Aalto University & KTH Royal Institute of Technology
Dual degree program as a part of EIT Digital Master School.

2012 - 2016

B.ENG. (HONORS) MECHANICAL ENGINEERING
Birla Institute of Technology and Science (BITS), Pilani
Graduated in First Division with a focus on 3D modelling.

Portfolio

www.guptasiddhant.com

Mail

me@guptasiddhant.com

Cal

+358 40 540 5535

Location

Otaniemi, Espoo, Finland

Profile

linkedin.com/in/guptasiddhant9

EXPERIENCE

OF 5 YEARS

2019 - Present

UX DESIGNER

FA Solutions Oy, Helsinki, Finland Web UI, Service Design, UX Testing

2018 - 2019

UI / UX DESIGNER

Freelancer in Espoo, Finland
Branding, Mobile UI, Web UI, UX Testing

2017 - 2018

UI DESIGNER

Freelancer in Stockholm, Sweden

Front-End Web-Dev, Mobile UI

2016 - 2017

DESIGN EXECUTIVE

Sprint Middle East LLC, Dubai, U.A.E.

Branding, Mobile UI, Web UI, Prototyping

2015 - 2017

CO-FOUNDER & UI DESIGNER

QB Middle East FZ-LLC, Dubai, U.A.E.

Branding, Mobile UI, Web UI, Prototyping

Summer of 2015

GRAPHIC DESIGN INTERN

ZIKR Studio, Delhi, India

Branding, Graphic design

2014 - 2016

GRAPHIC DESIGNER

BITS Pilani FZ-LLC, Dubai, U.A.E.

Brochures, Banners, Magazines.